あたしは運命って言葉が好き
だって　運命の出会いって言うでしょ
ただ一つの出会いが その後の人生をすっかり変えてしまう
I love the word "fate".
そんな特別な出会いは偶然じゃない
You know how they talk about "fated encounters"?
それはきっと運命
Just one single encounter can completely change your life.
うん　これから　貴志とデート
大丈夫　今日はトリプルレースで勝負
Such special encounters are not coincidences.
かけてくから
They're definitely... fate.
もちろん人生には幸せな出会いばかりじゃない
Yeah, I have a date with Takashi.
It'll be fine. I've got my triple-lace lingerie on... to seduce him!
嫌なこと　悲しいことだって　たくさんある
自分ではどうしよもない
Of course, life is not all happy encounters.
そういう不幸を運命だって受け入れるのはとても辛いこと
There are many painful, sad predicaments.
でも　あたしはこう思う
悲しいこと辛いことにも きっと意味があるだって
It's hard to accept that misfortunes beyond your control are fate.
無駄なことなんて一つもない
だって　あたしは運命を信じているから
But I think...
sad and painful things happen for a reason.
くるくる回る
Nothing in this world is pointless.
君の瞳探して回る
駅のホーム
Because... I believe in fate.
響くファンファーレ
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
御免ね
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
運命が笑う
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
臨界点突破してる
限界なら既に去って
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
絶対的支配だって
崩壊
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
叫ぶよ
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
僕は目を閉じるよ
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
本字幕由諸神字幕組製作，僅供交流學習，禁止用於商業用途
更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄www.kamigami.org
日聽：xHunter  日翻：沉默   喵西   校對：頠君子
時間軸：在端涯   壓制：呆狼
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
Kanba
Shouma
Himari
Takakura
いただきます
Let's eat!
そう言えばこいつら餌って何食べるだろう
That reminds me, what do these things eat?
Fortune
Probably fish?
魚じゃないの　ペンギンなんだし
They are penguins, after all.
イワシとか鰺とかサバをあげるって水族館のお姉さんは言ってたよ
The lady at the aquarium said she feeds them sardines and mackerel.
イワシ　サバ　鰺
Sardines and mackerel?
It's going to cost a fortune to feed them!
それでも物凄く餌代がかかるってことじゃないか
よし　ししゃも食うぞ
Oh! They eat shishamo too!
安い動物フードとかじゃだめかな
I wonder if cheap dog food will do.
生存戦略！
Survival Strategy!
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Night
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Fight
I'm just a Rock'n Roll Man
We're just a Rock'n Roll BAND
俺たちは道なりに　歩き続けてきた
標識だらけの道を飛ばし続けていく
幾つもの町を抜け　歌い続けてきた
腑抜け野郎共を煽り続けていく
長い長い冬が溶けても風が吹く
今も今も激しく風が吹く
Imagine!
きっと何者にもなれないお前たちに告げる
Listen, you lowlifes who will never amount to anything.
What, what, what?!
やっばりこの間のは夢じゃなかったのか
So it wasn't a dream!
何処にあるんだよ
Where is the "Penguin Drum" you spoke of?
そのピングドラムってのは
本日午前八時十分発の列車に乗れ
Get on the train departing at 0810 hours today.
前から三行目　二番目のドアで待機
Wait in the third car, by the second door.
Ringo Oginome will get on at Higashi-Koenji Station.
東高園寺駅で荻野目リンゴが乗車する
荻野目リンゴ
Ringo Oginome?
She has the Penguin Drum.
そのものがピングドラムを持っている
多分な
Probably.
What do you mean, "probably"?
なんだよ　多分って
What, do you have a problem with that?
何
気に食わぬのか
妹はどうなってもよいのだな
Don't you care what happens to your sister?
We will gladly serve you,
喜んで遣れせていただきます　帽子様
O' Magnificent Hat.
You must find the Penguin Drum at all costs.
よい　必ずやピングドラムを見つけ出すのだ
If you fail, consider your sister's life forfeit.
もしそれが叶わぬ時には妹の命はないものと思え
No way...
そんな
でも　多分とかそんな適当なことで責任を取らせるなんて　あまりじゃねねね
But making us pay for something based on a "probably"
is unfair!
生存戦略しましょか
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.
そもそもペンギン帽
That penguin hat...
No, that mysterious alien life form showed up on the day we went to the aquarium together as a family.
もとい
謎の宇宙生命体家にやってきたのは
久しぶりに家族三人で水族館に行った日の事だった
They said there was nothing modern medicine could do for my sister.
現在の医学では治療不可能と言われていた難病の妹は
確かに一度死に
She really did die once and the hat resurrected her.
そして あれのおかげで生き返った
Today's
Slogan
まるで 神様が冗談半部に仕組んだ意地の悪いゲームのように
Like a vicious game set up by God.
Molest and be arrested!
あれは生存戦略のため
It tells us to find the Penguin Drum in order to initiate the Survival Strategy.
僕たちにピングドラムを探せという
Shoma - Front train car - Sister ressurects
* Mysterious incident, it was not a dream. Then what was it?
ね　兄貴
Say, Bro...
荻野目リンゴってどうな人なんだろうね
What kind of person do you think Ringo Oginome is?
She's riding the train at this hour, so she must be an office worker or a student.
この時間に電車使うなら　OLか学生か
どうちらにせよ
In any case, she should be easily recognizable since we weren't told anything about her.
何も言わなかったってことはすぐ分かるだろう
Our task is to obtain the Penguin Drum.
俺たちはピングドラムを手に入れるだけだ
これじゃ　誰が誰だか分からないよ
We can't tell anyone apart in here.
いいや　こんな時こそあいつらが…
Those guys are perfect for this situation.
Right!
そうか
無理だよ　あいつらじゃ
They're useless!
もうー　何やってんだよ
Sheesh, what are you doing?
You!
ちょっと
うん？
Huh?
へえじゃないわよ
Don't 'huh' me!
あんた今　私のお尻触ったでしょ
You just groped my ass, didn't you?
N-No, I didn't!
そんなことしてないよ
嘘よ　くりくりいって触り巻くってたじゃない
You're lying!
You were feeling me up all over.
誤解だって
That's a misunderstanding.
それは
It was...
それは？
It was?
What was it?
何よ
それは今君の足に踏まれているペンギンみたいの生き物のせいで
It was that penguin-like creature
that you're stepping on right now.
しかもそれは ペンギン帽子方をした地球外生命体の女王
Not only that, they're servants brought by that penguin-
hat-shaped-extraterrestrial-humanoid-princess (probably),
カッコ多分カッコ途中が連れて来た家臣達って
僕たち家族にしか見えないです
and only members of our family can see them...
なんて言っても 絶対信じてもらえないだろうし
But there's no way she'd buy that...
What do you have to say for yourself?!
黙ってないで　なんとか言ったらどうなのよ
悪い　それは俺のせいかもしれね
Oops, maybe it was my fault.
鞄挟まれてて
My bag was stuck and I yanked it out.
先無理やり引き抜いたから
悪気は無かったんだ
I didn't mean any harm.
でも　不愉快の思いをさせたのなら　謝る
But I apologize for any discomfort I may have caused...
御免
I'm sorry.
うん　そういうことなら
Oh, if that's what happened... Well, I guess it was unavoidable.
ま　仕方ないかな　込んでるだし
It's crowded, after all.
じゃ　私たちここで降りるから
Well, this is our stop.
行こう　リンゴ
Let's go, Ringo.
Huh? I'm missing a shoe.
あれ　靴が片一本ない
何処
Where is it?
お前は降りろ
You get off.
あの制服は桜花御苑女子だ
That uniform is for Ohka Garden Girls' High.
兄貴は
What about you?
先に行ってろ
Go on ahead, I have to prepare something.
ちょっと準備だ
What?
いた
There they are.
'Morning!
お早う
Yamashita...
山下
What's up? You seem so grumpy this early in the morning.
何だよ
朝っぱらから不景気な顔しちゃて
What is it?
どうした　恋の悩みか
Girl problems?
Sorry, go on without me today!
悪い　今日は先に行ってて
なんだ　なんだ
What's going on?
お子ちゃんマの晶馬にLove到来か
Baby Shoma finally found love?
せっかく見つけられたんだから
We've actually found her! We have to obtain the Penguin Drum now!
ピングドラムを手に入れないと
For Himari!
ひまりのために
Ohka Garden Girl's High School
靴どうする
What are you going to do about your shoe?
Watch out for molesters
I'll just go barefoot today.
今日はずっと裸足でいいか
G-Girls' school...
女子高
女子高ね
Girls' school, huh?
ふー　どうする
What should I do?
Cross-dress?
女装でもする
Do you want to?
したいのか
Where were you, bro?!
兄貴　何処行ってたんだよ
ちょっとな
Taking care of a little business.
マアー　とにかくこれを見ろ
Anyway, take a look at this.
Kayo Aida
Ohka Girl's High School
Student Counseling Report
Mayu Itoh
こんなもの　何処で
Where did you get something like this?
うん　昔の女でそういうのに強い女がいてな
Tomoko Enoki
I used to go out with a girl who was good at this kind of thing.
Ringo Oginome
What kind of thing?
強いって？
ハッキング
Hacking.
それ犯罪じゃ
That's illegal.
Hey, let me borrow yours.
おい　ちょっとお前の貸せ
ええ　何？
What is it?
二？
Two?
This guy is Penguin #1.
こちのがペンギン一号
で　そちのが二号
And that's Penguin #2.
ひまりと家にいるのが三号
The one in home with Himari is #3.
面倒がなくて　いいだろう
It's easier to distinguish them.
That's so random.
適当な
そして　さらは
And finally...
Ohka Garden Girl's High School
大　大丈夫かな
Is this really going to work?
よし　いいぞ
Good, keep going.
Keep going forward.
そのまま真っ直ぐだ
Right there, go up those stairs.
そうだ
その階段を登れ
左から三番目の教室だ
It's the third classroom on the left.
そこが二年Ｃ組だ
That's class 2-C.
Walk to Canossa
窓際の席に向かえ
Head to the seat by the window.
よし
Yes...
Bingo.
bingo
Check her belongings.
持ち物を探れ
何か怪しいものは持ってないか
See if she has anything suspicious.
Hey, do you really think we should be doing this?
ねね　本当にこんなことしていいのかな
How else are we going to investigate a total stranger?
じゃ　どうやって赤の他人を探るんだよ
ばれなきゃ大丈夫だろう
She'll never find out.
別に誰を傷つけるわけじゃなし
It's not like we're causing anyone harm.
違うよ
That's not what I meant.
モーラルの問題だって言ってるの
It's a moral issue.
ペンギンが他の人には見えないからって
This is still a crime even if no one can see the penguins.
それが犯罪
じゃどうやって探すんだよ
How are we supposed to find it?
手に入れないと　ひまりが死ぬ
Himari will die unless we get it.
頼んでほよほよくれるはずねんだろう
There's no way she'll hand it over if we just ask.
The end justifies the means.
手段とか選んでる場合か
やるしかないだろう
We've got to do it.
ひまりのためなら
For Himari.
Ringo can't see the penguins
お腹空いたね
I'm hungry, Threetie.
三ちゃん
Should I make something to eat?
何が作ろうか
What would you like?
なにがいい
This?
これ？
Let's see...
何　何
"Double-H recommends the Healthy Menu."
ダブルエッチのお勧め
ヘルシーメニュー
はい　高倉です
Takakura residence.
Hello, is this Takakuras'... younger sister?
ああ　もしもし　高倉君の妹さんかな
担任の多蕗です
This is their homeroom teacher, Mr. Tabuki.
Swallow's Nest
ねねねね　凄くカッコよかったんだって
...and like, it turns out he's like, way hot!
I apologize for any displeasure I may have caused.
不愉快の思いをさせたのなら謝る
I'm sorry.
御免
Like that! Right, Ringo?
なんて
な　リンゴ
いいな　私も見たかった
I'm so jealous! I wish I was there.
あれはかなり来た
That really made my heart skip a beat.
So, what about the guy you suspected at first?
それで最初疑わしい子はどうだったの
Ordinary people can't see the penguins
うん　一緒にいた子はね
The guy with him was really... dull, I guess.
超空気って感じだったんだけど
ちゃんと監視しろよな
Keep watch from a distance!
I think that uniform was West Garden High's.
あの制服ってさ　外苑西高だと思うんだよね
No way! They're pretty close, then.
嘘
News
Red-rumped swallow's nest in Tokyo
じゃ　すぐ近くじゃ
News
Red-rumped swallow's nest in Tokyo
リンゴ
Ringo?
What's wrong?
どうかした
It's nothing.
うん　なんでもない
さては私のタコさんウインナを狙ってたの
Were you trying to steal my octopus-shaped wieners?
て　あれ　ない
Huh? They're missing... Did you eat them already?
食べだっけ
I finished my lunch, sorry.
ううん　いらない　御免
あたし　今日はちょっと先に帰るね
I have to leave early today.
Ringo Oginome lives by Higashi-Koenji, right?
荻野目リンゴって家東高円寺だったよな
She's going the opposite direction.
自宅とは反対方向だね
何かあるな
She's up to something.
Bro, what exactly is the Penguin Drum, anyway?
ね　兄貴
うん？
ピングドラムってさ　そもそもなんなだろうね
Hell if I know.
知るかよ
一号も二号も分からないみたいだし
#1 and #2 don't seem to know either.
And that penguin hat isn't telling us.
あのペンギン帽も何なのか言わないしね
ああ　まったく想像がつかん
I don't have the faintest idea.
本当に僕たちが取ってこれるものなのかな
Is it really something we can get our hands on?
とにかく探して取ってこいというからには
She did ask us to find it and bring it to her,
何か形のあるもの なんだろうよ
so it must be tangible... I would think.
僕たちはただ 帽子の言うままにピングドラムを探すしかない
We can only do as the hat ordered us and search for the Penguin Drum.
For Himari.
ひまりのために
男は胃袋
Seize a man's heart through his stomach.
Wear sexy lingerie everyday.
下着は毎日が勝負
It looks like she's just browsing through the bookstore.
何か普通に立ち読みしてるだけみたいだけど
油断するな
Don't let your guard down. She might be leaving secret messages.
何か暗号とか残していくかもしれないだろう
What is she, a spy?
まさか　スパイじゃまるまいし
Idiot! Why didn't you set it to silent?
馬鹿　マナーモードにしとけよ
Sorry, sorry!
御免　御免
Hello?
もしもし
お兄ちゃん
Shoma? Where and what are you doing?
今何処で何してるの
何処って…ええと…
Where?
I'm in... a bookstore.
本屋さん
Is it Himari?
ひまりか
You two skipped school, didn't you?
お兄ちゃんたち　今日学校サボったでしょ
ええ　何で知ってる
How did you...
Mr. Tabuki was worried and gave me a call.
多蕗先生が心配して電話くれたんだよ
Shoma!
晶馬
あちだ
She went that way.
Sorry Himari, I'll call back!
御免　ひまり　またかけ直す
ああ　お兄ちゃんたちが不良になっちゃたらどうしよう
What should I do if my brothers turn into delinquents?
御免よ　ひまり
Sorry, Himari!
お兄ちゃんたち頑張るからね
Your brothers are doing their best!
こ…これは…
I-It's...
下着ショップか
A lingerie shop?
This place... is out of bounds for sure!
ここは　絶対無理だ
まさか　あれがピングドラムなのか
Could that be... the Penguin Drum?
ええ　あんなの僕買えに行けないよ
What?
I can't possibly buy that!
I guess not.
違ったか
おいおい　もっと過激なやつだってか
Geez, could it be an even more eccentric one?
もしかして　あちの穴開いてる凄いやつだったりして
Maybe that one with all the holes!
N-No way, seriously?
嘘　マジで
Which holes do their legs go through?
あれ　足は何処の穴に入れるだよ
Fool, those holes lead to the cosmos.
馬鹿　あの穴は宇宙に繋がってるだよ
You're not making any sense!
意味分からねー
もう　早く出ようよ
Let's leave already!
ここにはピングドラムはないで
The Penguin Drum isn't here.
あれ　あれ　何処行った
H-Huh? Where did she go?
兄貴が馬鹿なこと言ってやがる
We've lost her because of your nonsense!
おれのせいかよ
It's my fault?
くそ　何処行きやがった
Damn, where the hell did she go?
Bro! Look!
兄貴　あれ
What?!
Why is she out there?
なんであんなところに
セーフ
どうする　兄貴
What do we do, bro?
マー　ここはこいつらだろう
Let's leave it to these guys.
You sure?
They really are useless.
やっば無理だったか
見つけた
Found you!
A shutter sound?
シャッター
She took a picture?
写真を撮ってるのか
誰かと待ち合わせかな
She's waiting for someone?
Yeah.
アア　先の奇妙の行動からして
Judging from that peculiar action, it could be someone involved with the Penguin Drum.
ピングドラムに関連する相手かもしれないな
What did she go to such lengths to take a picture of?
なんなことまでして
何の写真撮ってたんだろう
Who knows?
さあなー
But that picture may very well be the Penguin Drum.
でもあんな写真がピングドラムってこともあるよな
動いたぞ
She's on the move!
多蕗さん
Mr. Tabuki!
アア　リンゴちゃん
Oh, Ringo!
兄貴　あれは
Bro... is that...
Yeah.
ああ
You're on your way home from cram school?
今日も御塾の帰り
最近よく会うけど　随分頑張ってるね
We've been running into each other a lot lately.
You must be studying really hard.
ええ　マアー
Yes, I am...
Oh, good timing!
あ　ちょっと良かった
あたし多蕗さんに見てもらえたいものがあったんです
I wanted to show you something.
ほら　凄いでしょ
See? Isn't this amazing?
The one in Ikebukuro you told me about last time!
この間話してくださった池袋の
腰赤燕(こしあかつばめ)の巣
A red-rumped swallow's nest?
Whoa! This is rare footage!
これはレアだな
But how did you take this picture?
でも　こんな写真どうやって撮ったの
A swallow's nest?
燕の巣お
内緒です
It's... a secret.
Well then, tell your mother I said hi.
それじゃ御母さんにもよろしく
気を付けて帰るんだよ
Be careful on your way home.
Yes, thank you.
はい　ありがとうございます
Hey.
おい
うん
多蕗のこつけて　どういうつもりなのがな
Why on earth is she tailing Mr. Tabuki?
あの女　多蕗に惚れてるな
She's fallen for Mr. Tabuki.
なにそれ　どういうこと
What?
What do you mean by that?
You're so dense.
お前　本当に鈍いな
よし　名誉挽回だ
All right, go redeem yourselves!
She's not there?
いない？
なんだ
What is that?
よし　入れ
Okay, go in.
トリプルレースか　勝負パンツだな
Triple-lace?
She's going all out with that lingerie.
What are you staring at, Bro?
何処見てんだよ　兄貴
おい
Look.
A journey in search for wild birds in across Japanese towns,
Episode 18, Kenji Miyazawa's hometown, Hanamaki city in Iwate Prefecture...
あの子　まさか
Don't tell me... she's...
It seems like she's doing to
Mr. Tabuki what we're doing to her.
どうやら　多蕗に対して俺たちと同じことをしてるみたいだな
つまり　荻野目リンゴは
In other words, Ringo Oginome is...
Mr. Tabuki's stalker.
多蕗のストーカーってことだ
...the wind also reminds you of summer.
It's a perfect season for birdwatching.
Yes.
Most birds will enter migration...
仕事の後はコーラが美味いな
An ice-cold cola after work is the best!
There's already a bird in our sight.
Don't worry. Your days of eating dinner alone are almost over.
安心して
一人の晩御飯も あと少しで終わりだよ
だって　これからはずっとあたしが一緒だもん
After all... I'll always be with you from now on.
My dear Tabuki, I won't let you feel lonely.
多蕗君の寂し思いなんて させない
It's okay. The future is already written right here.
I found a swallow's nest in Ikebukuro. Tabuki was really surprised when I showed him the picture.
大丈夫
未来は予め すべてここに書いてあるから
無駄なことなんて一つもないよ
Nothing in this world is pointless.
I believe in fate.
あたしは運命を信じている
Destiny
Destiny.
Risky Survival Strategy
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
全てがもし
決められてたら
僕らはどうして
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
もがくのだろう
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
それは君じゃない
君のせいじゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
悲しみはもう沢山なんだ
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
だからそうじゃない
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
今のままじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
上手く伝えきれないけど
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
Dear my future
Dear you future
Dear your future
No matter how risky, we will do
whatever it takes to save Himari's life.
たとえどんなにやばいことだろうと
ひまりの命を救えるのなら
俺たちはやるしかないんだ
They're pretty small
Hey!
Lily Hoshino
本字幕由諸神字幕組製作，僅供交流學習，禁止用於商業用途
更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄www.kamigami.org
日聽：xHunter  日翻：沉默   喵西   校對：頠君子
時間軸：在端涯   壓制：呆狼
Should we initiate the Survival Strategy?
生存戦略しようかな